Hello. I'm Jay, and in this lesson,
大家好 我是 Jay 这节课
we'll be talking about dimensionality reduction.
我们要讨论的是降维
The first method we'll look at in this lesson is random projection,
我们学习的第一个方法是随机投影
which is a powerful dimensionality reduction method
这是一个很有效的降维方法
that is computationally more efficient than PCA.
在计算上比主成分分析更有效率
It is commonly used in cases where a dataset has
它通常应用于 当一个数据集里有太多维度
too many dimensions for PCA to be directly computed.
主成分分析无法直接计算的情境下
Let's say your application is running on a system with limited computational resources,
假定运行你的应用程序的系统计算资源有限
or you just find that PSA's too taxing for a specific situation that you're in.
或者你发现 在你所处具体情境下 主成分分析太繁重
Just like PCA, it takes a dataset.
就像主成分分析 这需要一个数据集
Let's say this is our dataset with d dimensions, let's say a thousand,
假定这是我们的 d 维度数据集 设 d 为 1000
and certain number of samples are rows,
及某些样本数组成行
let's say N. So these are our columns.
设其为 N 所以这些是我们的列
So it takes our dataset and it produces
它需要我们的数据集 并将其转化成
a transformation of it that is in a much smaller number of columns,
数量少得多的 k 个列
so k, let's say 50,
此例中设为 50
for example here, but the same number of samples.
样本数不变
And each column here,
此处的每个列
it captures information from multiple columns there.
从另一处多个列中采集信息
Let's look at an oversimplified example for
我们来看一个简单化的例子
reducing the dimensions of a dataset from two dimensions into one dimension.
将一个数据集的维度从二维降至一维
So PCA here would try to maximize variance.
主成分分析会试着将方差最大化
So it finds the vector or direction that maximizes the variance.
它寻找将方差最大化的矢量或方向
So it loses the least amount of information when it
所以 当它将数据从二维投影为一维时
projects the data from two dimensions to one.
它损失最少的信息
And so that line would be something like this,
那这条线就会像这样
and these would be the projections.
这些就是投影
And so in one dimension,
在一维里
the dataset would look like this.
该数据集看上去就是这样
A random projection, so this calculation that PCA did,
随机投影 进行主成分分析做过的计算
especially if you're talking about a lot of dimensions,
尤其是存在很多维度时
it consumes a certain amount of resources.
它会消耗一定量的资源
Random projection just say,
随机投影只是表示
we'll just pick a line, any line.
我们会选择一条线 任何一条
We'll do a projection on that. That's our dataset.
在那条线上进行投射 这就是我们的数据集
And so while it doesn't really make a lot of sense in a scenario,
它在某些情境下没有太大意义
in our oversimplified scenario like this from two dimensions to one,
在我们简化了的从二维到一维的情境下
it actually works, and it works really well in higher dimensions.
它其实是有作用的 在更高维度的效果更好
It works in a high-performance way.
且工作效能很高
The basic premise of a random projection is that we
随机投影的基本前提是
can simply reduce the number of dimensions in
我们可以用数据集乘以一个这样的随机矩阵
our dataset by multiplying it by a random matrix like this.
来减少其中的维度数量
And so d, we will have d in our dataset,
我们的数据集里有 d
but k is something we either compute,
但是 k 要么是我们计算的
or it's something we desire.
要么是我们要得出的
And there is a way to compute what is a conservative or
我们也有方法可以计算 k 的一个保守估计
a good estimate for k. And so that would be the resulting dataset,
或合适的估值 这就是产生的数据集
just multiplying by a random matrix.
乘以一个随机矩阵
That's all random projection is in a way.
在某种程度上 这就是全部的随机投影
Let's take a concrete example here.
我们举一个具体的例子
Let's say this is our dataset,
假定这是我们的数据集
and it has 12,000 dimensions,
它有 12000 个维度
and that's our d,
这是 d
and it has 1,500 rows or samples.
它有 1500 行或样本
If we give this to Scikit-learn and say, "Okay, Scikit-learn,
如果我们把它交给 Scikit-learn 问它 “Scikit-learn
can you please do a random projection for this dataset just using your default values?"
你能只用默认值对这个数据及进行随机投影吗？”
it will return this dataset for us,
它给出的是这个数据集
which will be in 6,200 dimensions and same number of samples, obviously.
它有 6200 个维度 显然样本数不变
So how do we know that it works,
我们怎么知道它起了作用呢？
and where does k come from?
我们怎么知道 k 是怎么来的呢？
The theoretical underpinning for
支撑随机投影的
random projection is this idea called the Johnson-Lindenstrauss lemma,
是 Johnson-Lindenstrauss 引理
which states that a dataset of N points in high-dimensional space, so this dataset,
该引理认为 处于高维度空间的 有 N 个点的数据集 比如这个数据集
endpoints high-dimensional space 12,000 is pretty high, it can be mapped,
12000 的高维度空间端点很高
that's just multiplying by this random matrix,
只要乘以随机矩阵
down to a space in much lower dimension,
就可以被映射成很低维度的空间
which is this narrow dataset.
即这个缩小的数据集
In a way, and this is why it's really important for us in a way,
某种程度上这就是它的重要之处
because it can be done in a way that preserves
因为它可以在很大程度上
the distances between the points to a large degree.
保留点之间的距离
So the distances between each two points,
所以该数据集投影后
each pair of points in this dataset after projection,
每两点之间的距离 每对之间的距离
that is preserved in a certain way.
在某种程度上可以得到保留
And that's really important because in most or in
这很重要 因为在
a lot of supervised and unsupervised learning,
大部分或许多监督学习与非监督学习中
the algorithms really care about the distances between the points.
很多算法和点之间的距离大有关联
And so, we have a certain level of guarantee that
所以我们要保证
these distances will be distorted a little bit,
这些距离会有些失真
but they can be preserved.
但可以得到保留
How can they be preserved?
那如何保留呢？
What sort of guarantees we have?
我们又如何保证呢？
Let's take a quick example and actually calculate that out.
我们简单举个例子来实际计算一下
So let's say, we take the first two rows here.
假定我们取这里的头两行
So this one and this one,
这一行和这一行
the first two points in our dataset.
我们数据集里的头两个点
And then these are their values after projection,
这就是它们投影后的值
so same samples but different level of dimensionality.
即 同样的样本 不同的维度水平
And so what the Johnson-Lindenstrauss lemma tells us that the distance
Johnson-Lindenstrauss 引理指出 投影后两点距离的
between the two points in the projection squared is sort of squeezed by,
平方值稍有压缩
so it's larger than the distance between the two points in
它大于原数据集里两点距离的平方值
the original dataset squared times one minus epsilon.
乘以 (1-eps) 的值
So epsilon is, sort of,
Epsilon 就类似于
the level of error that we are allowing the random projection to have in the projection.
我们在此次投影中可接受的随机投影的误差
So the distance between the two points in the projected dataset will be larger
所以 投影后的数据集里两点距离
than one minus epsilon times
大于 (1-eps)
square of distance of the two points in the original dataset,
乘原数据集里两点距离的平方值
and it will be smaller than one plus epsilon of that distance squared.
且小于 (1+eps) 乘原数据集里两点距离的平方值
I've actually calculated those numbers.
我实际上算出了这些数字
So the distance between these two points is 125.6.
这两点之间的距离为 125.6
So we put that in here.
我们放在这里
Epsilon, the default value,
Epsilon 的默认值
so we didn't change anything,
我们没做任何改动
the default value in Scikit-learn is 0.1.
在 Scikit-learn 里的默认值就为 0.1
It can take any value from zero to one.
它可以取 0 到 1 的任何数值
So if we do it like this,
如果我们像这样做
the distance between these two points is 125.8.
这两点之间的距离为 125.8
And so, this distance here will be larger than
那么 这个距离会比该距离平方值的
0.9 times this distance and smaller than 1.1 times this distance squared.
0.9 倍大 且比该距离平方值的 1.1 倍小
And so you can see that epsilon is sort of like a liver.
你会发现 Epsilon 有点像一个操纵杆
It goes into the calculation of how many columns are produced,
它用于计算产生了多少列
and it is the level of error that we are allowing
并且是我们在此降维中可接受的
the distortion to have in this reduction of dimensionality.
失真的误差水平
So this guarantee happens,
这就产生了保障
preserves the distance between every pair of points in the dataset.
保持了数据集里每对点之间的距离
So it's not just one and two,
这不仅是关乎 1 和 2
it's one and every other point,
它关乎 1 和其他任何点
and two and every other point.
关乎 2 和其他任何点
So that guarantee is there,
在该保障下
and epsilon is just an input into the function that we can use to,
Epsilon 只是经我们输入到函数中
say, preserve the distances by this degree.
用来在此程度上保持距离